准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
章鱼鸽
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
终于刻画出了火热的激情  那就是
Finally, I've captured the firey passion that is
我
moi
怎么就进来了一只蛤蜊
How did a clam get in here?
倒要给你看看玷污我艺术品的下场
I'll show you for defiling my art
看你干的好事
Look what you've done
我的半身像碎了
My bust is busted
好啊  有信
Oh boy, a message
你好  派大星
"Hello, Patrick
嗨面包包寄
From Sprog-Bub"
神秘寄信人
A mystery sender
就你了
Gotcha
一路顺风
Safe travels
出去
Get out
好啊
Oh boy
派大星回信了
Patrick responded
有点像是鸡鸭互相接吻
It's a duck and a chicken kissing, I think?
马上回来  小蛤蜊
Be right back, clammies
你好啊  章鱼哥
Hello, Squidward
你这是在试用新款防晒霜吗
Are you trying out a new sunscreen?
什么
What?
才不是
No
都是那群死蛤蜊害的
It's those stupid clams
为什么非得飞过我家
Why are they flying through my house?
那些都是信蛤
They're carrier clams
我和派大星在互相飞蛤传书
Patrick and I are sending each other messages
你们家的无脑死蛤蜊
Well, your brainless bivalves
进了我家窗子  糟蹋了我家艺术品
are going through my windows and destroying my art
你们向我保证
Just promise me
飞蛤传书别传进我家来
you'll stop sending your clams through my window
看你背后
"Behind you"?
我们保证
We promise
宁静舒适
Peace and quiet
一定是我订的大理石板到了
That must be the new marble slabs I ordered
你好
Hello
什么
What?
又来几只蛤蜊
More clams?
绷不住了
That is it
现在得要让我亲爪解决了
Time to take matters into my own tentacles
不能笑章鱼哥社死  不然没礼貌
It's rude to laugh at Squidward's hilarious shame
派大星  我把午饭送过去
Patrick, I'm sending over lunch
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
我都饿坏了
I'm starving
祝你们炖汤愉快
Have fun at the Chowder Factory
杂烩汤厂
成功了  章鱼哥
You did it, Squidward
终于把那群死蛤蜊赶走了
You finally put a stop to those stupid clams
蛤蜊杂烩汤
好耶  杂烩汤
Oh boy, chowder
谢谢你送吃的来  海绵宝宝
Thanks for the grub, SpongeBob
你们炖汤愉快不
Did you have fun at the Chowder Factory
杂烩汤好烫
Hot chowder
好了  章鱼哥
All right, Squidward
打不过就无视好了
If you can't beat 'em, ignore 'em
章鱼
Hey, Squidw--
太好了
Great
白痴大游行过来表演了
The idiot parade is in town
不对
Oh, no
得等五月才能过来
We don't meet until May
还是旧月来着
Or was it Septebuary?
我只是在让我家信蛤
I'm just having my carrier clams
送我去海绵宝宝家
carry me to SpongeBob's house
这样去比较轻松
It's easier this way
我来带你抄近道
Allow me to show you a shortcut
剪
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
谢了  兄弟
Thanks, buddy
旧月再见
See you in Septebuary
你怎么这么久才来
What took you so long?
我路上堵车
I ran into traffic
还撞了别人家
And the house
那群蛤蜊也太爱章鱼哥了吧
Those clams sure do love Squidward
好像章鱼哥不怎么爱蛤蜊
Well, I'm not so sure he loves them
我们得给蛤蜊训练一下  专门避开他
Maybe we should train our clams to avoid him
没错
Oh yeah
就跟别人一个样
Like everybody else does
蛤蜊点心
不
No
恭喜毕业
不好了
Oh, no
蛤蜊来了
Here they come
怎么
What the--
不行
No
起码我这回穿好了衣服
Well, at least I'm not naked this time
在左边  能看到一只光着身子的章鱼
And on your left, you'll see a naked octopus
裤头村观光团
被反锁在自家门外
locked out of his house
再也受不了了
I can't take it anymore
必须以火攻火
I'll have to fight fire with fire
在这
Over here
请你在这签名签收包裹
Sign here to accept the package
再在这签名
and sign here
接受伤残以及死亡的可能性
to accept possibility of injury maiming, or death
很高兴能认识你  朋友
Nice knowing you, pal
我的秘密武器总算到了
Finally, my secret weapons
大扇贝
A great scallop
杀手蛤蜊真乖
Nice killer clam
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
这里有自助餐吃
Well, here's a whole buffet
进攻
Sic 'em, boy
现在谁家蛤蜊厉害了
Who's got that clam now?
我家厉害
I do
我家扇贝最厉害
I got the greatest scallop
哇  章鱼哥
Wow, Squidward
它们好漂亮
They're so pretty
快看
Look
我买你来是要吓跑那群死蛤蜊
I bought you to scare those dumb clams
不是跟着一起跳舞
not dance with them
要来了
Incoming
屋主回家一定会气疯的
Boy, is that guy gonna be mad when he gets home
完全躲不开
There's no escaping them
我们完蛋了
We're doomed
振作点  章鱼哥
Cheer up, Squidward
至少我们还有彼此
At least we have each other
那种事可让我振作不起来
That doesn't cheer me up
蛤蜊好像都走了
I think the clams left
蛤蜊都没走
The clams didn't leave
也许可以等它们全都迁徙完了再出来
Maybe we can just wait 'em out until they migrate?
没错
Yeah
再等六个月又怎样
What's another six months?
六个月  六个月
Six months, six months
怎么回事
What's happening?
我们貌似在迁徙
I think we're migrating
派大星  执行流星行动
Patrick, commence operation Shooting Star
什么  你意思是说要跳窗吗
What, you mean, like, jump out of the window?
没错
Yeah
就是要跳窗
Jump out the window
好
Okay
快跳啊  章鱼哥
Jump, Squidward
跳
Jump
完蛋  我越飞越远了
Oh, no, I'm getting farther away
等一下  我越飞越远了
Wait a minute, I'm getting farther away
再见了
So long, boys
我总算远走高飞了
I'm finally moving on up
还是比住海绵宝宝隔壁强
Still better than living next to SpongeBob
过敏来袭
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
千千万万亿
走过路过都来看看
Come one, come all
新闻
别错过我的专业煎炸厨师  海绵宝宝
Don't miss my expert fry cook, SpongeBob
做出第千千万万亿个蟹黄堡
cookin' his one kazillionth Krabby Patty
入场费只要五块钱
Entry fee is only five clams
我是帕奇帕金斯  在蟹堡王现场直播
Perch Perkins here, live at the Krusty Krab
于今天这个重大日子为你现场报道
bringing you the play-by-play on this momentous day
煎炸厨师登场了
The fry cook of the hour
海绵宝宝先生  你有何感想
Mr. SquarePants, how do you feel?
不敢相信真的成真了
I can't believe it's really happening
今天是我厨师事业中最重要的日子
This is the biggest day of my fry cook career
来见见今天的幸运顾客
Let's meet the lucky customer
他将会吃到这个非凡的蟹黄堡
who gets to eat the marvelous patty
海霸王
Bubble Bas--
那个蟹黄堡肯定平平无奇
I'm sure the patty will be mediocre
但凡事我都必须争第一
but I must be first at everything
快给我
Give me that
找点有意义的事做吧
Get a life, people
才一个蟹黄堡而已
It's just a patty
是不是很神啊  章鱼哥
Isn't it amazing, Squidward?
如果我是在做第千千万万亿个蟹黄堡
If I'm making the kazillionth patty
那你就接了千千万万亿个点餐单了
then you've written a kazillion orders
不用你提醒
Don't remind me
章鱼哥先生  你害海绵宝宝分心了
Mr. Squidward, you're distractin' SpongeBob
现在我们要前往蟹堡王的厨房
We now take you live to the Krusty Krab's kitchen
直播蟹黄堡制作实况
for the main event
海绵宝宝为接下来的任务进行准备
SpongeBob prepares himself for the task ahead
他切菜的模样仿佛一位雕刻大师
He's chopping the veggies like a master sculptor
他在测试面包的弹性
He's testing the bun's elasticity
他在挑选
He's picking
表面干燥变硬程度最低的肉饼
a patty with the least amount of freezer burn
冻肉饼
看看它多闪耀啊
Look at it sparkle
开始做蟹黄堡了
The patty is in play
重复一遍  开始做蟹黄堡了
I repeat, the patty is in play
这厨艺展示得属实优美
What a fantastic display of fry cook skills
你能不能动作快点
Will you hurry it up already?
等一下
Hold on
海绵宝宝似乎有些分神了
SpongeBob seems distracted
出了一点小问题
Something's wrong, folks
煎炸厨师起了某种疹子
The fry cook has broken out in some kind of rash
一定要做
Must fini--
做
f--
做完
finish
恶心
Disgusting
上菜了  海霸王
Here you go, Bubble Bass
我做的第千千万万亿个蟹黄堡
My kazillionth Krabby Patty
刚煎好  热乎着
hot off the grill
这我可吃不下
I can't consume this
你这可怜的蟹黄堡
You poor Krabby Patty
实在太不卫生了
This is so unsanitary
够了
That's it
我这就走
I'm outta here
等等  别走
Wait, don't go
抱歉  小子
Sorry, boy-o
我不知道你是怎么了
I don't know what's goin' on with you
可你坏了我的生意
but you're ruinin' me business
要是我做不了蟹黄堡  那我是谁
If I can't cook Krabby Patties, then who am I?
疹子太该死了
Curse this blasted rash
我的疹子
My rash?
没有了
It's gone
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板  我康复了
Mr. Krabs, I'm cured
你样子感觉一点都没康复  小子
You don't look cured to me, son
我康复了
I'm cure--
没
Nope
我康复了
I'm cure--
出去
Out
我会想你的  蟹黄堡
I'm gonna miss you, Krabby Patty
我
What's
这是怎么了
Happening to me?
这还不明显
Isn't it obvious?
你对蟹黄堡过敏了
You're allergic to Krabby Patties
刚刚收到的消息
This just in
海绵宝宝对蟹黄堡过敏
SpongeBob's allergic to Krabby Patties
对蟹黄堡过敏
Allergic to Krabby Patties?
这里有专治过敏的医生吗
Is there an allergist in the house?
我就是过敏专科医师
I'm an allergist
我先
Dibs
说  啊
Say Ah
嚏
Choo
过敏专科医师笑话
Allergist humor
由于长期暴露在蟹黄堡附近
The constant exposure to Krabby Patties
导致你产生了过敏性免疫反应
has caused a hypersensitive immunological reaction
你说什么
Say what now?
蟹黄堡会让你发痒
Krabby Patties make you itch
不过你放心
But don't worry
我能治好你
I can cure you
慢着
Hold it
海绵宝宝只是需要
SpongeBob just needs
与过敏原进行隔绝
to be isolated from the allergen
也就是跟蟹黄堡进行隔绝
In this case, Krabby Patties
我刚好会帮他隔绝
And I know just how to do it
虽说我的旧潜水服有点笨重
My old divin' suit's a little bulky
不过可以保护你
but it'll keep you safe
把你跟四散的蟹黄堡颗粒隔开
from any stray patty particles
谢谢珊迪
Thank you, Sandy
碰碰运气吧
Here goes nothing
是不是很棒啊  章鱼哥
Isn't it wonderful, Squidward?
我又能做蟹黄堡了
I can cook Krabby Patties again
好好好好好
Whoop-dee-diddly-doo
好  开做了
Okay, here we go
一点点这个  一点点那个
A little bit of this, a little bit of that
再一点这个
Some of this
好了
Got it
一份蟹黄堡  双倍腌椰菜
One Krabby Patty with double pickle
不加海草酱
hold the kelp-sup
抱歉
Sorry
两个蟹黄堡  再加一份珊瑚薯条卷
Two patty singles with an order of curly coral bits
我就快掌握诀窍了
I'm gettin' the hang of it
抱歉
Sorry
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
抱歉
Sorry
我不能就这样工作
I can't work like this
抱歉
Sorry
学会蹲下  章鱼哥
Learn to duck, Mr. Squidward
抱歉
Sorry
下班了
Quittin' time
终于啊
Finally
我才刚会用这套衣服
Just when I was gettin' this suit figured out
怎么回事  海绵宝宝
What's goin' on in here, SpongeBob?
我脱不掉这身衣服  回不了家了
I can't take this suit off and I can't go home
怎么办  蟹老板
What'll I do, Mr. Krabs?
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
从今往后你只能睡厨房里了
You'll have to bunk in the kitchen from now on
万岁
Hooray
在工作岗位过夜
Work sleepover
你放心  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
我早就想到你有可能会不方便回家
I figured you might have a little trouble
getting back to your homestead
所以我就带了点日用品
so I brung along some supplies
好耶
Yeah
我也忘不掉这个小家伙
And I couldn't forget this little feller
几天后
不好了
Oh, no
客人们也对蟹黄堡过敏了
the customers are allergic to patties too
快  进潜水服里
Quick, get inside the suit
进来会比较安全
You'll be safe in here
我的疹子消失了
My rash is gone
完全康复了
Totally cured
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
怎么了
Yes?
干什么
Why?
海绵宝宝失去理智了
SpongeBob lost his marbles
他把客人全吸进那个疯狂装置里了
He sucked all the customers
into that crazy contraption
蟹黄堡过敏症在到处传染  蟹老板
The patty allergy's spreading, Mr. Krabs
客人们也都过敏了
The customers are allergic too
冷静点  小子
Calm down, lad
你一定是有些言过其
I'm sure you're just exaggerat--
你别怕  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
我来救你了
I'll save you
舒服多了
That's better
章鱼哥  快进衣服里
Squidward, get in the suit
别让过敏给传染了
Don't let the allergy get you
不行
Oh, no
我才不住进那个铁罐子里
I'm not living in that tin can
更何况你还在里面
especially with you inside it
快点  章鱼哥
Hurry, Squidward
现在还来得及
Before it's too late
快回来
Come back
我过来看看
Just checkin' in to see
你怎么样了
how y'all are doin'?
好家伙
Whoo-doggy
这里样子乱糟糟的
Looks like a cattle drive came through here
你们都没事吧
Y'all okay in there?
没事
Yeah
我很有事
No, I am not
这衣服臭死了
This suit smells revolting
还好我有新买的古龙水
Good thing I have my new cologne
头足香料
Cephalopod Spice
你们打喷嚏不是因为蟹黄堡
Y'all weren't sneezin' from patties
是对章鱼哥的便宜货古龙水过敏
You're allergic to Squidward's cheap cologne
我要让你们知道我的清香型香水
I'll have you know that my eau de toilette
可贵了
is tres pricey
潜水服把过敏原集中在一起了
The suit's concentrated the allergen
你们的疹子变严重了
Y'all's rashes are goin' critical
很久以后
一份蟹黄堡
One Krabby Patty
不会害人过敏
Allergy-free
起码我还有古龙水
At least I still have my cologne
果不其然
Typical